[{"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Do you enjoy traveling? Tell me about your favorite destination and one destination that is on your bucket list.", "answers": ["Being away from home so often can be tough, so be sure to express your interest in travel and new experiences. As a flight attendant, you will have the opportunity to fly to many different locations. The interviewer wants to be assured that you would enjoy this aspect of the job, so be open and honest about your favorite destination and your bucket list destination.", "\"I absolutely love to travel. My family traveled a lot when I was growing up and it seems that I caught the travel bug too. My favorite destination so far has been Barbados, and Spain is on my bucket list of places I would love to go.\"", "\"Travel is the main reason I chose to pursue a career as a flight attendant. I love flying out to Southeast Asia. The layover in Hong Kong to Thailand is one of my favorites because of the food. Now, I've never been to Scotland, and I'd love to go there to see the landscape there.\""]}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "If you were asked to take a flight across country and back unexpectedly, how would you handle this?", "answers": ["The life of a Flight Attendant can involve the need to be very flexible in your work hours and flights that you are scheduled to work.  With this question, your interviewer is looking to delve into how flexible you can be, if hired for the position.  As you answer, be sure to be open and honest about your personal life and your availability to be scheduled on short notice.  Discuss with the interviewer how you would react in a situation like this.", "\"I am more than happy to do what it takes for the good of my company and team. My previous supervisor commented often on my willingness to take long shifts whenever required.  I am very fortunate to have a flexible family life at home and the ability to work when called upon. I would accept the opportunity and maintain a positive attitude.\"", "\"I understand that this job may have unexpected flights. I don't have any problem with it. I have a friend who can take care of my home while I'm gone, and my father can take care of any bills. They've been helping me with that kind of thing for a while, so they know what to expect. I'm happy to take on any assignments that come up unexpectedly.\""]}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Why do you want to work for this airline?", "answers": ["With many airlines to choose from, your interviewer will be looking to hear why you have a passion and commitment to their airline.  This is where it is very helpful to have conducted some research on the company prior to your interview. To really sell your interviewer on your passion and commitment to this job, try to match your own personal goals and values with that of the airline.", "\"I have a particular interest in your airline because of your strong reputation in the industry and the dedication you have to positive customer experiences. I have flown your airline as a first choice for the past 5 years and have not been disappointed in the quality service delivered. I'd love to be a part of that.\"", "\"I've heard a lot of good things about this airline. I really like the way the company treats its employees. For example, I think it's great how the company will stand up for employees if a customer gets way out of line because sometimes customers will take advantage of a company's generosity, which really just encourages bad behavior from all the customers. It also shows me that the company is great at diplomatically handling confrontational situations, which is a skill that I'm really interested in building. And on top of that, this airline travels to all the places that I want to go, as well as others that I haven't been to yet.\"", "\"American Airlines is my dream airline, they are the biggest and the best, and I've always believed in shooting for the stars.  I also love their cultural diversity and treating others with respect, but what is near and dear to my heart is their dedication to the American Airlines cadet program that encourages young girls and boys in the scouts to pursue pilot careers. Overall I love that AA is on the cutting edge of technology because great is what I'm going for!\"", "Fantastic response! Any interviewer should appreciate your energy. Your answer also shows the depth of research you have committed to."]}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "How would you handle a situation in which a passenger keeps breaking basic flight rules, such as wearing their seat belt?", "answers": ["As a Flight Attendant, you will often come across passengers who simply don't care about the rules and regulations of flying. Talk to the interviewer about your strategy for dealing with these types of passengers.  In your answer, try to demonstrate that you would be firm, respectful, and professional in your approach with that passenger.", "\"In my current Flight Attendant role, I have been trained to handle uncooperative passengers in a variety of ways. If reasoning with them does not work, I will then ask them to personally suggest what a reasonable solution may be. If they are unwilling to reason with me, I will remove myself from the situation and ask another Flight Attendant to step in.\"", "\"I've been trained to handle unruly passengers in a number of ways. Usually, these kinds of passengers don't respond well to people who try to exert authority onto them, so I explain to them that government regulations require passengers to be wearing their seat belts at this time, and that it was for the safety of all the passengers. I'd explain to him what would happen if he didn't have his seatbelt on during sudden turbulence. If he still refuses, then I'd emphasize the rules again and ask him what his suggestion is.\""]}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Describe a situation when you were able to have a positive influence on the actions of others.", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "If you were in an unknown city, what would you do to find a restaurant?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Tell me what you know about our airline.", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Do you have a current passport?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "If you had a passenger who couldn't keep calm due to anxiety of a plane crash, how would you calm them down?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "How would you rate your people skills?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "How would you handle a situation where one passenger complained about the passenger next to him for snoring too loudly?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Do you get motion sickness?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "How tolerable are you of people?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "How long do you see yourself as a flight attendant?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "When did you realize you wanted to become a flight attendant?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "What type of emergency training have you completed?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "If a passenger got violently ill during a flight, how would you handle this situation?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Have you ever had a stranger yell at you before? How did you handle the situation?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Why do you think passengers take their frustration out on the cabin crew, even though the crew is trying to help them?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "What are your compensation expectations?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "How do you feel about the dress code and professional standards?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "At your current job, what are you most proud of?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Have you ever been on a team where someone was not pulling their own weight? How did you handle it?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "What would you do if you saw one of your colleagues deliberately being rude to a passenger?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Give me an example of a time that you went above and beyond the call of duty at work.", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Describe a situation when you demonstrated initiative and took action without waiting for direction. What was the outcome?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "What do you think the flight attendant's primary responsibility is as a crew member?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Are you applying for any other jobs?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Are you okay with being on a long layover?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Where would you like this career to take you?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Tell me about yourself.", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "How do you believe your coworkers would describe you?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "What is your availability?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Do you prefer doing work on a routine day-to-day basis or do you prefer mixing up your routine occasionally?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Think about a difficult boss, professor, or other person you've worked with. What made them difficult? How did you successfully interact with this person?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Why are you the best candidate for us?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Would you consider yourself a creative person?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "How would you calm an irate passenger that would not take no for answer?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "How would you define excellent customer service as a Ticket Agent?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Tell me about a time where you had to deal with conflict with a co-worker. How was the situation resolved?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Are you striving for a leadership role in the future?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "What is your ideal company culture?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Why should we hire you?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Walk me through your experience in customer service based roles.", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "What are your career goals?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "How do you handle stressful situations?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Excellent communication skills are required to be successful as a Ticket Agent.  How would you rate your communication skills?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Give us an example of a time where you provided excellent customer service.", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Describe a time where you had to overcome a big challenge.", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "How would your most recent supervisor describe your work ethic?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Attendance on the job is very important. Tell me about your attendance record and punctuality in your previous role.", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Ticket Agents are required to be available to work many variable hours.  Are you able to work weekends, evenings or overtime as needed?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "As a Ticket Agent, you will be working very independently.  How do you keep your manager informed about what is being done in your work area?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "How do you feel your education has prepared you for this role?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Ticket Agents have to work with a high sense of honesty and ethical principles.  How have you shown integrity in your work in the past?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "In your opinion, what are the top 3 skills required to be a successful Ticket Agent?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "What personality types would you say that you work the best with?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "How would you multitask many different customer requests and duties at one time?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Do you have direct experience working in a retail setting or customer cash transactions?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Working as a Ticket Agent involves some serious physical demands.  Are you able to meet the physical requirements of the job?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "How do you feel about wearing a company uniform on the job every day as a Ticket Agent?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Ticket Agents are often asked to abide by specific safety and security protocols on the job.  Have you had to work with these types of protocols in previous work?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Have you every had a job where you provided service over the phone?  What key skills from that experience would you bring with to this role?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "If you were on the phone with a customer that was demanding that you match the ticket pricing of a competitor airline, how would you handle that situation?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "If hired as our next Customer Service Agent, you would be expected to train diligently on our software programs during your orientation process so you can hit the ground running.  How would you rate your ability to do this?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Have you had any cash handling experience during your career at any point, as it would relate to customer transactions?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "How would you describe your communication style?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Describe a time you had to explain something complex to a colleague or customer.  How did you handle this conversation to ensure that the message was conveyed?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "As our next Customer Service Agent, you will be expected to know many facets of our business.  Have you ever held a role where knowing your business from back to front was necessary for your role?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "At times in this role, you may be required to transport passengers via a shuttle van.  Do you have a valid driver's license and a clean driving record?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Our Customer Service Agents often have to handle unique requests from our customers with a smile on their face.  Talk about a time you had to handle a unique request that fell outside of your typical job duties.  Why did you oblige the request?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Our Customer Service Agents help with ensuring that aircraft are prepared for flight inside the cabin.  Do you have any cleaning and/or stocking experience during your career?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Part of this role will entail escorting passengers to and from flights in a timely manner.  What interpersonal skills do you have that will make you excel in this aspect of the job?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Our staff are expected to withhold the highest standards of professionalism while on the job.  What does being professional mean to you on the job?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "In this role, you would be expected to come to work each shift in uniform and neatly groomed.  Would you have any issues in doing this?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Talk about a time that you identified an area for improvement on the job in the past.  How did you go about ensuring that changes were made, and why did you take this course of action?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Talk about a job where you had to multitask your duties each day.  What did you do to stay organized and on task throughout the day?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Our Customer Service Agents need to know and adhere by the FAA's regulations and policies on a daily basis.  Have you worked in a job in the past where adherence to local, state, or federal laws was important?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Safety and security are extremely important in the airport setting.  How can you help foster a culture of safety for our staff and customers?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "This position would require a background and employment verification check.  Would you have any issues being subjected to this?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "What appeals to you most about being our next Customer Service Agent?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Talk about a time you had to deal with an unreasonable person in the workplace.  How did you handle that situation with ease?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Our Customer Service Agents need to have the ability to say no to our customers at times. How would you approach a customer who is hoping for a ticket on an upcoming flight that is sold out?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "If a customer approached you with a question or request that you weren't sure how to respond to, what would be the next steps you would take?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "At our airline, teamwork is the key to providing the best overall experience to our customers.  How do you work as part of a larger team?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "What is one advantage that our airline has over our competition?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "What do you consider your greatest accomplishment during your career?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Our Operations Agents need to be very highly organized on the job.  How do you ensure that your workload stays organized and on track?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Do you have any direct experience in shipping and receiving duties throughout your career?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Our Operations Agents need to be the ultimate team players among our entire staff.  What makes you a great team player?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Tell me about a time you had difficulty working with a colleague.  What did you do to try and help that situation?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Tell me about a time you had to have a difficult conversation with a colleague.  How did you handle that situation to ensure it was successful?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "If hired as our next Operations Agent, I will expect you to build a solid rapport with all of the people you will be working closely with.  How would you go about doing this?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Have you ever had a time where your workload became too unbearable?  How did you handle this situation?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Our Operations Agents are relied upon to make sound decisions on a turnaround almost every day.  Have you ever had a time where you had to be quick in coming to an important decision on the job?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "How skilled are you in learning new computer software programs?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "What is the highest level of mathematics that you completed during your education?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "If hired as our next Operations Agent, where do you see yourself five years down the road?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "To be successful as an Operations Agent with us, being diligent about attention to detail on the job is important.  Why do you think being very detail-oriented is important for this role?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Which part of this position as an Operations Agent do you feel you would excel at?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "If hired as our next Operations Agent, would you bring any bilingual skills to our team?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "How would you keep yourself motivated and upbeat on a day where customers are being very difficult to work with?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "If hired as our next Operations Agent, what would providing excellent customer service look like to you?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Talk about a time you had to settle a conflict in the workplace.  What were the important things you did to ensure that this happened in a safe way that ended well?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Talk about a role you've held in the past where problem solving was an essential part of the job?  What did you learn in that role that you can bring to our team as an Operations Agent?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Have you ever went above and beyond the expectations of a customer or colleague to provide excellent service?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Let's say you had to let an overweight passenger know that they would have to purchase two seat tickets on a flight.  How would you approach that passenger?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Talk about the position you've held during your career where you faced the most amount of pressure.  How did you perform well under this pressure?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Do you have any pet peeves in the workplace?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Why are you interested in working for our airline?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "The Operations Agent that we hire for this role needs to have a strict focus on safety.  What aspects of safety do you envision being responsible for in this job?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Has a colleague every tried to encourage you to cut corners at work?  How did you handle that situation?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "What skills do you think are most critical to working as a Ramp Agent?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Have you ever had to perform record keeping duties on the job in the past?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Why are you the best candidate for this role as a Ramp Agent?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "How would you rate your communication skills  and why do you feel these skills are important for a Ramp Agent?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "What experience do you have, that I can't see on your resume, that you feel prepares you well for work as a Ramp Agent?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Working as a Ramp Agent will require you to work any shift on any day of the year.  Can you work weekends and holidays in this role?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "How do you foresee yourself working in a very fast paced environment as a Ramp Agent?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Give an example of a time you had to take a leadership role on the job.  What did you learn from that situation?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Which responsibility on the job posting do you consider the most challenging, and why?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "What would a previous supervisor say about you and your work ethic, if I were to ask?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "What do you look for in an employer?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Tell me about an accomplishment that you are the most proud of.", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Tell me about a success you had with an especially difficult coworker.", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "How do you assign priorities and manage time in your current job?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Describe a recent unpopular decision you made on the job.  What was the outcome of that decision?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Working as a Ramp Agent comes with some physical demands.  Do you think you are able to handle the physical requirements in this line of work?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Have you ever had to work in extreme weather conditions in any of your previous positions?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Do you have a valid driver's license and a clean driving record?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "How have you prioritized working under strict safety protocols during your career?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Talk about your experience working as part of a larger team.  In what role are you most comfortable on a team?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Would you consider yourself able to work independently with little direction?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "This job as a Ramp Agent will require some basic computer skills.  How would you rate your computer skills?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Working as a Ramp Agent requires mechanical aptitude to help troubleshoot equipment issues on the fly.  How would you rate your mechanical aptitude?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Do you have any experience operating heavy equipment?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Are you comfortable with heights?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Why did you choose a career as an Aircraft Maintenance Technician?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "What subject, during your maintenance training, was the strongest?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "What do you excel at as an aircraft maintenance technician?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "How active are you in your job search?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Do you have your own tools?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "If you fail to do your job correctly, what are the consequences? Are you able to work under that kind of pressure?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "What do you enjoy most about working on aircraft?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Tell me about your education and training.", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "How well do you know your ATA codes?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "What aircraft inspections do you dislike doing?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "What is the latest news you've heard about our airline?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "What is your aircraft maintenance specialty?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Would you rather work for a commercial or private airline? Explain your answer.", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Have you always had a strong mechanical aptitude?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "What protective gear are you accustomed to wearing on the job?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Are you able to work outside in extreme weather conditions, if required?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Would you ever consider skipping an inspection?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "In what situation would you would work on an airplane without proper engineers authorization?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "How important is safety to you?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "How do you like to be recognized for your accomplishments?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "When have you had to adapt your workload due to increasing demand from your supervisors?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "By this time in your career, you should have advanced further, what has slowed down your career progression?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "How would you describe your work ethic?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "Would you say you are a better verbal or written communicator?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "When have you worked with a diverse group of people?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "How many days were you absent from work last year?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "When have you shown great integrity at work?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "What is your current salary?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Airlines", "question": "When would you be available to start?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Public+Transit", "question": "Do you have experience in dispatch or radio communications of any kind?", "answers": ["Depending on the role to which you are applying, it may be a significant asset to have dispatch or radio communication experience. Public transit, to operate smoothly, has many moving parts behind the scenes. These moving parts include dispatch so that everyone knows their place, where they should be, and when! \n\nIf you do have dispatch experience, outline the type of equipment you have used and the volume that you can handle. If you do not have dispatch experience, discuss any experience with radio communication equipment. If you are new to your career, this question may not apply, but you should always show an eagerness and willingness to learn.", "\"I worked as a dispatcher for a commercial trucking company earlier in my career, for about four years. The equipment that I used included two-way radio and a GPS based computer program. I was amazed by how much work goes into the logistics of transportation and time-optimization for deliveries and driver schedules. Although dispatch is no longer a part of my career, I certainly have a strong appreciation for the profession and understand its importance.\"", "\"I understand how to use a two-way radio, and I have a solid understanding of GPS based computer systems. Dispatch is an important component of public transit, and I am eager to learn more.\""]}, {"topic": "Public+Transit", "question": "Although we have an excellent training program at Company ABC, we are seeking to hire someone with an intermediate level of experience in our industry. With what types of transportation services are you most experienced?", "answers": ["Transportation types could include air, water, and land transport. Land transport could then include trains, buses, railways, and more. Take a few minutes to walk the interviewer through your experience, being sure to highlight the areas of transportation in which you bring experience.\n\nIf you are new to the industry or your career in general, speak more to the transferable skills you offer, and express your interest in jumping to this industry.", "\"Your training program is well known to be the best in the industry, and I look forward to learning a lot from your skilled teams. I have worked in transportation for ten years; primarily in commercial transport and trucking. I have experience with the transportation of dangerous goods as well. This experience has equipped me for a career in public transit as I am well-trained to put safety before anything else. I am also sensitive to and keenly aware of timing and deadlines.\"", "\"My experience comes from my education in Transportation Planning and Infrastructure. I recently graduated from this program and excelled in coursework in transportation demand analysis, Geographic Information Systems, and policy analysis and implementation. This education is all-encompassing, and I feel well-equipped to work with all forms of public transportation services.\""]}, {"topic": "Public+Transit", "question": "When working with the public, emergencies can happen. How will you react to unexpected stress and pressure?", "answers": ["Company ABC sees many passengers every day. With this type of traffic, emergencies are sure to happen from time to time. The interviewer needs to know that you can react appropriately and professionally under expected, high-pressure situations. Assure the interviewer that you can maintain your cool in emergencies, and while under stress. If you have a story to tell from a time when you helped during an emergency, be sure to bring this experience to life for the hiring authority.", "\"A few months ago, one of our passengers had a heart attack during the morning commute. Another passenger pushed the emergency button, so I pulled the vehicle over at the first safe opportunity, while also telling someone with a cell phone to call 911. I assessed the passenger in distress and kept them comfortable until paramedics arrived. Luckily, we covered this type of situation in my operator training. I believe that this training gave me the confidence to react swiftly and appropriately. You can see from this example that I can follow protocol, act quickly, and remain professional under stress and pressure.\"", "\"I understand that Company ABC has guidelines, protocols, and formal training for many types of emergencies. I am a naturally calm and confident person who likes to help people so, for those reasons, I have every reason to believe that I would react appropriately and thoughtfully if faced with an unexpected situation.\""]}, {"topic": "Public+Transit", "question": "As a public transit operator, you will meet hundreds of new people every day. In which ways do you embrace diversity?", "answers": ["Diversity and inclusion are important topics at Company ABC and the interviewer would like to know that you share a mindset of inclusion and equality. The interviewer wants to see that you understand the importance of acknowledging people different from you. This acceptance may come in the form of being kind to the people that you meet and treating everyone the same. Discuss how you embrace diversity in your personal and professional life.", "\"I too am a minority so, I appreciate it when someone else reaches out to learn about me and my culture. I fully recognized the needs and the difference in the needs of others. For me, embracing diversity encompasses culture but also gender identity, age, and more. I am sensitive to and very accepting.\"", "\"I appreciate that Company ABC is so open when it comes to conversations around diversity and inclusion in the workplace. I celebrate those different from me and take every opportunity to learn about what makes them unique. I recognize that everyone has a story, whether that be related to gender identity, sexual orientation, or heritage, for instance.\""]}, {"topic": "Public+Transit", "question": "Do you have your air brakes or Q endorsement?", "answers": ["This question is highly targeted and will have a response of either yes or no. The interviewer would like to see you elaborate a little bit on your reply, either way. \n\nIf you do have your air brakes or Q endorsement, discuss when you obtained this driving credential. Be prepared to present any certificate or proof in your interview as the hiring authority may want to take a copy for your candidate record. \n\nIf you do not have your air brakes or Q endorsement, be sure to express to the interviewer the steps you are willing to take to gain that credential.", "\"I do have my air brake endorsement, and have so for the past eight years, along with my CDL (commercial drivers' license). I brought proof of endorsement with me today, and you are welcome to take a copy for your records.\"", "\"I have not yet earned my air brakes certification; however, I am currently in the process of completing the training. My coursework comes to an end this month.\""]}, {"topic": "Public+Transit", "question": "How would you go about asking for a change in the workplace if you did not like the current approach?", "answers": ["Many public transit jobs are government-run, managed by the city in which you work, or backed by a union. The interviewer would like to know that you can professionally navigate the landscape when it comes to asking for change at Company ABC or even making suggestions and recommendations. Discuss how you would approach asking for a change in the workplace if you were unhappy with the current situation. Show that you are confident enough to approach a subject but also professional enough to know how to go about it. If you have a specific example of a time when you did ask for change, tell the interviewer about the action that you took.", "\"As the lead dispatcher in my current company I felt that the hours we were asked to work were become less reasonable every week. When I first started the job, I would bank around five overtime hours per week. Now, on average, I am asked to work at least 15 overtime hours per week. Of course, I comply as often as I can, but it is not in anyone's best interest to have overexerted employees. I approached our union rep about my concerns, and we crafted a plan to have a productive conversation around the issue. My suggestion was to hire two new full-time employees to equal the 45+ hours of overtime banked every week. The request is still in review; however, I feel great about the way I handled my concern.\"", "\"When I first joined my last employer, I noticed that the company did not have a workplace harassment and bullying policy. Coming out of university and being very sensitive to the diversity and inclusion conversation, I felt I would bring a fresh perspective to my employer. I requested a meeting with the management team, where I brought up my concerns, along with concrete examples that I had seen in our work environment. The leadership team thanked me for my concerns and for being so alert and sensitive to potentially bigger issues over time. As a result, they granted me the title of 'Diversity Liaison' where I am an appointed safe place for anyone feeling uncomfortable for any reason.\""]}, {"topic": "Public+Transit", "question": "What do you know about the Company ABC training program?", "answers": ["You will find information on the Company ABC website, by researching online, or simply by asking! It's essential that, before taking any job, you understand how dedicated the company is when it comes to equipping you to do your job. Do your research, and if you have any questions for the interviewer, this is an excellent time to ask! \n\nSome questions that you could ask about the training program include: \n\n- How long is the training? \n- Who will be training me?\n- Will I be paid during the training period? \n- What are the expectations of me once training is complete? \n- Is training performed both in the field and in a classroom setting?", "\"I read on your website that your training consists of two weeks in-class training, one week job shadowing another operator, and another week of supervised fieldwork. I understand that I will be required to pass my driving test by at least 85% along with additional testing such as language skills and physical health. I took some time to read through the employee reviews on Glassdoor and noticed there was a common theme surrounding the fact that your training is some of the best in the industry. I found that very exciting to read.\"", "\"I know that your training program is four weeks long and the working hours during the training program are 7:30 a.m. to 4 p.m. Monday to Friday. From what I have read, the first six days of the training program are focused on bus driving. During that time, I will be required to pass a Class II road test. I read that there will be several homework assignments for me to take home and complete. Before being on my own, I will complete another two driver evaluations and a written exam. I appreciate that your training program is so thorough as I will, no doubt, feel very confident in my driving skills once the program is complete.\""]}, {"topic": "Public+Transit", "question": "How would you handle a passenger complaint?", "answers": ["Public transit is, essentially, customer service. When you work with the public on this level, it's essential that you handle every situation appropriately, quickly, and with the utmost care. Bad reviews stay forever (thanks, Internet!) so it's crucial to Company ABC that you handle any passenger grievance carefully.\n\nMost people recommend taking the following actions: \n\n- Stay pleasant, positive and professional\n- Carefully listen to their issue \n- On behalf of the company, give a sincere apology\n- Keep neutral and avoid becoming defensive\n\nDiscuss what you would do, step by step, to handle a passenger complaint.", "\"If faced with a passenger complaint, I would first make sure that I had a full understanding of the situation and what went wrong. I would apologize on behalf of Company ABC and ask the passenger what I could do to make the situation better. There is value is making people feel heard and important.\"", "\"I worked in customer service while attending university and received a fair amount of training when it came to customer complaints. I would handle passenger complaints at Company ABC with the same care and attention. The steps include stop, make eye contact, listen, repeat back, and resolve. If the situation were more serious than a general complaint, I would escalate the concern to my direct supervisor.\""]}, {"topic": "Public+Transit", "question": "What do you know about Company ABC and the people we serve every day?", "answers": ["It is imperative to the interviewer that you show excitement for the job. Part of this excitement is engagement in the interview process. Essentially; that means coming well-prepared and well-researched. Imagine going on a first date, and they know nothing about you? That's how offended an interviewer would be if you knew nothing about their company before attending an interview. Perform research on Company ABC through a search engine and their website. Check out any awards they may have received, any news surrounding growth and infrastructure development, and of course, check out employee and customer reviews. You should know around how many people they serve every day, how long they have been in business and other key talking notes.", "\"I know that Company ABC has been around since (enter year), and that you serve around (#) passengers per year. The reviews that I have read from customers consistently say that they appreciate the ease of use and affordable transit passes. Other compliments online included mentions of your clean environment and helpful staff. \"", "\"I have been a passenger of Company ABC for four years now, taking the train everywhere I go. My first-hand experience tells me that you serve thousands a day that are getting to work, school, and their extracurricular activities. You serve passengers from all walks of life, and all ages. I especially appreciate that you (mention a recent award, innovation, or mention in the news).\""]}, {"topic": "Public+Transit", "question": "Are you prepared to present your driver's abstract from all jurisdictions that you have been a licensed driver in the last two years?", "answers": ["If you are interviewing for an operator role of any kind, Company ABC will likely require you to present your drivers' abstract. Each company you talk with will have specific requirements as far as how far back they look into your driving history, and in what region; if you have relocated recently. The best thing to do is to keep your response short and concise! Of course, you are willing to present whatever documentation they require for your employment records.", "\"I have brought with me today, an original copy of my drivers' abstract for the last three years. I have lived in this region since 2005 so everything you need will be available here, in this state. Is there anything more I can provide for my candidate file?\"", "\"I recently moved here from (name region), so I took on the task of ordering the past two years of driving history from that area, as well as the past six months here, in (name region). If there is anything further that you need, I am happy to comply.\""]}, {"topic": "Public+Transit", "question": "What do you know about public transit rules, regulations, and safety compliance?", "answers": ["Rules and regulation surrounding safety and public transit use will change depending on the region in which you are interviewing. The hiring authority would like to know that you have at least a basic understanding of the industry before being hired. If you are new to the public transit industry, it is entirely acceptable for your knowledge to be limited. In this case, it is more important that you show a willingness to learn more about the industry.", "\"I have worked in public transit for fifteen years and am very familiar with the rules and regulations for operators and other employees in this industry. I know that Company ABC will have its own set of regulations laid out which I am more than happy to begin learning. Safety and compliance are topics of utmost importance to me.\"", "\"I fully understand why Company ABC would need to have strict rules surrounding public transit use, and compliance. If you could direct me on where to learn more about the regulations in our area, I would like to gain a head start on my learning.\""]}, {"topic": "Public+Transit", "question": "How will your education help you to succeed in this position with Company ABC?", "answers": ["Your education might be on your resume; however, the interviewer wants you to take a minute and bring that educational experience to life for them. \n\nSome areas where you could focus on include: \n\n- Awards or accolades you received \n- Specific classes where you excelled \n- Scholarships and grants you earned\n- Volunteer work while attending school\n- Clubs or groups with which you were involved\n- Your grades, or where you placed in your graduating class\n\nBecause this is an open-ended question, it can be easy to ramble on. Try to structure your response carefully to avoid a long-winded answer that confuses the interviewer. Be sure to tie in your educational experience with qualities and soft skills mentioned in the job posting.", "\"I had an excellent post-secondary experience and am happy to have earned my degree in Operational Management. My education will help me to succeed in this role with Company ABC as it provided me with a full understanding of how to manage many moving parts from the delivery of excellent customer service to emergency management, safety protocols, and maintenance needs. During my time in university, I played team sports, which also taught me a great deal about teamwork, training hard, and upholding a healthy level of competition both internally and externally.\"", "\"I recently graduated with my Diploma in Administration. The coursework that I took included accounting, supply chain management, and basic financial management. I graduated top of the class, all while working part-time. I learned skills such as organization, prioritization, and stress management. All of these skills will add to my success here at Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Public+Transit", "question": "Company ABC requires a security clearance check, positive references, and a medical examination before offering employment. Are you willing to comply?", "answers": ["The answer should always be that 'yes!' you are willing to comply. If you want the role with Company ABC you need to be prepared to have your background checked in all possible ways. These steps are very typical in the public transit industry. Answer in a way that assures the interviewer that you are willing to take any background checks they require.", "\"I completely understand the need for a variety of background checks, and you have my expressed permission to look into my work history, do a criminal background check, and ensure that I am physically able to do this job without injuring myself or others.\"", "\"I appreciate the hard work that goes into ensuring all new hires are qualified to be in a public service role. I am happy to comply with any background checks that you require.\""]}, {"topic": "Public+Transit", "question": "At Company ABC we strive to be the best transit agency in the world. How will you contribute to this goal?", "answers": ["The hiring authority wants to know that you understand and respect their goals as a company while bringing the enthusiasm required to succeed in your role. When everyone works towards one common goal, extraordinary things can happen! Discuss what you know they do best, and how you will contribute.", "\" While preparing for this interview, I read that your mission statement is to (insert company statement). I will help you to achieve this by (list three actions that you would take). It's important to me that my company be successful and gain positive customer reviews since my livelihood also depends on these factors. I take pride in my work and appreciate that Company ABC does the same.\"", "\"I plan to contribute to your goal of being the best transit agency in the world by being an engaged employee, keeping myself trained on the latest news and approaches in the industry, and continually seeking out ways to make the passenger experience more enjoyable. Many people spend hours a day commuting on Company ABC trains, so it's important that I acknowledge this, and make their experience exceptional every time.\""]}, {"topic": "Public+Transit", "question": "Company ABC oversees transit operations by use of computer-generated displays, and voice communications. Do you have experience in these areas? If not, do you consider yourself technically savvy?", "answers": ["In most roles with Company ABC you will be asked to communicate with your teammates and complete your duties, using a variety of tech and equipment. In the public transit industry, routes are computerized, everything is timed, and many tasks are automated. Be prepared to discuss your ability to learn these systems quickly.", "\"In my current role, we use a lot of technical equipment; primarily Motorola solutions including two-way radio, call handling software, dispatch consoles, video surveillance, and other network monitoring tools. I am confident in my ability to learn the tech used at Company ABC and will apply my existing knowledge as well.\"", "\"I am technically savvy and, although I am new to my career with limited knowledge of the tech used in public transit, I am sure that I will be a fast learner. I pick up on new tech all the time. If you would like, I am happy to get ahead of the curve by watching online tutorials on the equipment most commonly used here at Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Public+Transit", "question": "Have you ever been involved in writing, preparing, or training Standard Operating Procedures or an Emergency Response Plan?", "answers": ["Standard Operating Procedures, often referred to as SOPs, are laid out instructions that assist employees in completing complex parts of their job. Think of SOPs as a manual of sorts. An SOP aims to maintain quality, consistency in work, increase communication, boost compliance, and improve safety. \n\nAn Emergency Response Plan includes the steps that employees need to take when an emergency occurs. This document can consist of accidents or even lockdown procedures. \n\nIf you are more seasoned in your career, you may have had some involvement in either writing, preparing, or training new employees on Standard Operating Procedures and Emergency Response Plans. If so, briefly discuss your participation and how confident you feel with these types of responsibilities. \n\nIf you are newer to your career, you may have seen your company's SOPs or Emergency Response Plan but have not had involvement in their creation. Show that you have an understanding of their importance and express your willingness to learn how to prepare and train others.", "\"In my current role, I train many new employees on our company's emergency response procedures and some operating procedures as well; mainly on workflow. My training is in the ISO-9000 format. It's important that every SOP come with clear instructions, checklists, and charts so that they are simple for everyone to understand. I am comfortable with leading these projects but also appreciate a high level of involvement with all stakeholders to ensure that the SOP is all-encompassing.\"", "\"I have been given SOPs to follow and have read through my current company's Emergency Response Plan. I am eager and willing to become involved in the creation of these important documents as I grow in my career. I have strong writing skills, I am organized, and have that keen eye for detail required to write robust documents such as these.\""]}, {"topic": "Public+Transit", "question": "Have you been a regular passenger of Company ABC? If so, what has been your experience? What did we do well, and what can we improve?", "answers": ["The hiring authority would like to know what your experiences have been with Company ABC and if you have any suggestions for improvement; or, any compliments for them! If you do have ideas for improvement, keep in mind that this is not an opportunity to reinvent the wheel. You want to avoid sounding critical or coming up with a multitude of ways that you will 'save' the company. Give an honest and engaging overview of your experience with Company ABC. Remember to keep your tone positive!", "\"When I was younger and did not have a car, I relied on Company ABC for all of my transportation needs. I loved riding the train because I was able to get my school work done while on my commute, people watch, or relax. My experience was always positive, as the trains felt clean and safe. Security and emergency help was always nearby and the trains nearly always on time.\"", "\"I have used public transit to get me to special events where parking is limited. I found Company ABC transportation to be clean and reliable. My only recommendation, from what I hear from friends and family who take public transit, is that it would be great to have passes go digital. This way they can pre-pay with a credit card and show proof of purchase through their mobile device, rather than keeping track of a paper ticket.\""]}, {"topic": "Public+Transit", "question": "This position is physically demanding. Are you able to meet the physical requirements such as bending, crawling, crouching, lifting, and standing for long periods?", "answers": ["Look for an outline of any physical requirements in the Company ABC job posting, and role description. If for any reason, you are unclear on the expectations in this role, it is best that you ask for clarification. For instance, if the job posting refers to 'heavy lifting,' it would be wise to ask how heavy, how often, and for how long. \n\nIf you have any physical ailments, it is in the best interest for you and the company that you disclose this. You do not need to go into too much detail; however, you do need to be honest if anything hinders your ability to perform the physical duties safely.", "\"I read in your job posting that this role requires bending, standing for long periods, and heavy lifting. Could you please tell me more about the lifting component? Although I am in great physical condition, I believe my limitation would be around 30 pounds of lifting multiple times per day.\"", "\"I am in peak physical condition and come prepared to perform all of the duties mentioned in the job description.\""]}, {"topic": "Public+Transit", "question": "Are you aware that, in this role, you risk exposure to physical, electrical, and chemical hazards as well as harsh weather conditions?", "answers": ["Any risks in this role will be outlined in the Company ABC job posting and role description. With that said, the interviewer still wants to double check that you are aware of the potential risks in this role. Assure the hiring authority that you are prepared to put safety first in your new position. If you have worked jobs with similar threats in the past, be sure to mention this and how you expertly handled the potential risks.", "\"I have read your job posting and description thoroughly and am very aware of the potential risks. In my current position, I work outside in all weather conditions, often at risk for extreme situations. I take my safety training seriously and am confident in my ability to react quickly and appropriately to any dangerous situation.\"", "\"I am keen when it comes to my training and putting safety first. Rest assured, I am aware of the risks in this role, and will do everything it takes to ensure my safety, the safety of Company ABC passengers, and the well-being of my coworkers.\""]}, {"topic": "Public+Transit", "question": "Public transit operates 24/7. Are you willing to meet the scheduling requirements for this position?", "answers": ["Your schedule at Company ABC will depend on the role to which you are applying. It is safe to say; however, that you might not receive prime hours as a new hire. Since a lot of public transportation runs 24/7, it is critical that you show a willingness to work a variety of hours and act as a team player. If you have restrictions in your schedule, this is a good time to mention them.", "\"In your job posting you mentioned that most employees begin with a night shift and that Company ABC bases holidays and vacation time on a scale of seniority. I am willing to work my way into a daytime schedule and more vacation opportunities. At this time, I am unavailable on Monday evenings, due to a family commitment; however, I am available any other times.\"", "\"Yes, I am willing to meet the scheduling requirements for this position. I am eager to get started in my career and will do what it takes to be a team player.\""]}, {"topic": "Public+Transit", "question": "What do you believe to be the biggest challenge public transit faces today?", "answers": ["There are a few main themes in public transit when it comes to challenges and obstacles. These include safety and security, funding, changes in travel habits, technical innovation, and workforce development. The interviewer wants to see that you have an idea of these challenges and that you come from a place of understanding. Discuss one problem that you believe to be significant. This question is an opportunity for you to ask questions or showcase your industry knowledge. Your approach will differ based on your level of experience.", "\"I believe that one of the biggest challenges public transit faces today is keeping up with the technical innovation in the transportation industry, and then balancing the introduction of tech with the expectations of passengers and the public. Technological innovation is bringing around new options when it comes to travel, but it is also changing people's expectations. In my current company, we are looking at everything, including everything from mobile ticketing to real-time data collection and analysis capabilities.\"", "\"From observation, I think that a significant challenge that public transit faces could be safety and security. Issues that never go away include emergency preparation, crime reducing, and supporting 24/7 passenger safety. Could you tell me more about what Company ABC is doing to tackle these important issues?\""]}, {"topic": "Public+Transit", "question": "In the event of an accident, what procedures would you follow?", "answers": ["If you have any safety or emergency training, this is an excellent opportunity to walk the interviewer through the scope of that training. If you do not have emergency training, that is okay too! Most important here is the fact that the interviewer needs to see your ability to think clearly and rationally in the event of an accident or emergency. Assure the hiring authority that you would follow Company ABC protocol and training while remaining calm and professional.", "\"In the event of an accident, I would call 911 first. Then, I would fully assess the situation by following my company training and standard procedures. As per my emergency response training from my current role, it's important that I remain calm in the event of an accident; showing confidence to the passengers, allowing them to better cope with the situation at hand.\"", "\"In the event of an accident, I would follow Company ABC procedures, exactly. I am eager to absorb my training here and will be prepared to react professionally and calmly in situations that require a mature response.\""]}, {"topic": "Public+Transit", "question": "On a scale of 1-10; how well do you know our city and its infrastructure?", "answers": ["Answering a scale of 1-10 is a simple way for the interviewer to assess your current knowledge level. If you are interviewing for a role with public transit, it is essential that you have a solid understanding of how the city operates in terms of roads and infrastructure. You could give your response while also putting a spotlight on how long you have lived in the area, for instance. And, if you are new to the area that is okay too! Be honest about your lack of knowledge in this area; however, focus on the positive by highlighting your dedication to learning.", "\"I grew up in this city and have seen it grow from a mere 400K people to 1.2M over the past decade. I would say that I am a 9 out of 10 when it comes to my understanding of the transit, roads, and infrastructure. Things are always changing, as we continue to develop our rural and urban areas.\"", "\"I recently moved here and am very excited to get to know this vibrant city! I have been studying Google maps in preparation for a position within public transit, and will continue to do so until I can confidently say that my knowledge of this city is a 10/10!\""]}, {"topic": "Public+Transit", "question": "Tell me about a challenge in your current job that you have overcome.", "answers": ["Every job presents its unique challenges. The interviewer would like to know the most significant challenge, problem, or situation that you have had to overcome in your current role. \n\nYour answer to this question will reveal to the interviewer the seniority that you have, and the level of engagement that you bring to work. Discuss a time when you faced a significant challenge, being sure to clearly outline the situation, your actions, and the result. Remember: interviewers love specific numbers and quantifiable results!", "\"In my current role, timely and effective communication had been the biggest issue. This breakdown of communication was causing safety issues and costing the company a lot of money. After taking two weeks to research, craft a strategy, and put together a presentation on available tools, I approached our management team with the top three programs that could save us a lot of time and error. These options included Wrike, Slack, and Monday, which are all productivity and team-based communication tools. Management took the suggestions and implemented one of the applications across three departments; allowing us to more easily communicate without losing emails or letting important tasks fall off.\"", "\"As a recent university graduate, the biggest challenge that I faced was managing my courseload while also working part-time to pay my tuition. To stay organized, I used a lot of technology and practical applications such as iCal and Evernote. I also found a mentor who could help me to prioritize what I needed to do to launch my career in transportation. By reaching out and asking for help and advice, I was able to reach my goal of graduating top of my class while completing school debt free.\""]}, {"topic": "Public+Transit", "question": "At Company ABC we want to see everyone succeed and grow. If we hire you, how can we support your professional goals?", "answers": ["Many companies, including Company ABC are realizing how important it is to fully support their employees when it comes to their career aspirations. It's in everyone's best interest for you to be further educated, trained well, and supported healthily. \n\nAs many organizations turn away from the hierarchical organizational structure and lean more toward a flat organizational structure, you will start to see companies show more concern for the growth and development of their employees. Think about the type of role that you would like to gain over the next few years. What kind of further education and training would you need to take, to be eligible?", "\"I have professional goals which include promotion into an operational management position with Company ABC over the next five years. One factor I have considered is the fact that I would need to return to school to complete my Bachelor of Management degree to be an eligible candidate. I am just a few credits shy. I noticed that Company ABC offers a tuition reimbursement program which is very generous. If you could support my professional goals, this would be the best start.\"", "\"I genuinely appreciate this question and acknowledge the efforts that Company ABC puts into training and developing its employees. The first step for me would be to have access to a robust training plan since this is my first professional job since graduating. The more educated I am, the more comfortable I will be; ensuring better performance and faster growth within your organization.\""]}, {"topic": "Public+Transit", "question": "What would you do if your direct supervisor was challenging to get along with, or a poor communicator?", "answers": ["The interviewer is not saying that your supervisor in this role will be a difficult person; however, they do want to know how you handle workplace situations of all types. People have moments where they are bad communicators, and every boss has a bad day, so you already know that working for someone isn't always easy. \n\nTell the interviewer what you do to make sure that the lines of communication are strong, no matter how well (or not well) you mesh with someone on a personal level. Be sure to express the fact that you act professionally and are focused on doing an excellent job, regardless.\n\nFinally, if you feel it is appropriate to do so, you can ask the interviewer a bit about the working style of the person to whom you will be reporting.", "\"If my direct supervisor was challenging to get along with, or a poor communicator, I would take the time to learn what style of communication worked best for them. It is important that I meet people where they are, rather than expecting them to do things my way all the time. I am an exceptional communicator, which makes it easier for me to build rapport with people of all personalities and characteristics. How would you describe the working style of the person I would be reporting to, in this role?\"", "\"I am an independent thinker, and able to work well unsupervised, which means that if my boss were a poor communicator, I would look for a way to source what I need on my own. Being a recent university graduate, my research and independent study skills are sharp, so I would apply those same concepts to learning and performing my tasks at work. While attending post-secondary studies, I did have a few professors who were brief and disengaged. I was able to apply these concepts and still did very well in their classes.\""]}, {"topic": "Public+Transit", "question": "It appears that your background is not in public transit. Tell me which transferable skills qualify you for this position with Company ABC?", "answers": ["This question applies to you if you do not come from a job in the public transit industry, or if you are brand new to your career. Perhaps you come from Oil & Energy, Healthcare, Engineering, or even IT. No matter which industry you have worked in, there will always be transferrable skills that can qualify you to jump industries. If you have never worked before, you will have transferable skills from school, home, volunteer, or even team sports. \n\nExamples of transferable skills include: \n\n- Team leadership \n- Problem-solving \n- Data analysis \n- Industry knowledge \n- Organization and planning \n\nTake a look at the Company ABC job description and take note of the soft skills listed in the posting. These are the areas that you will want to be prepared to discuss if you are missing some of the industry-specific experience mentioned. When you craft your answer, rather than focusing on what you do not have, it's crucial that you focus on what you do have. This approach means that you should avoid starting your answer with 'Although I don't have...' or 'I do not have experience in...but...' \n\nThis question is an opportunity to sell yourself as the top candidate, so be prepared with a compelling response!", "\"I have many transferable skills from the chemical engineering industry, where I worked for 15 years. The Company ABC job posting mentions skills such as organizational planning, compliance, and a focus on safety. These were all priorities in my last position, and I plan to keep them as priorities in this role. Other skills that will lend to my success include my ability to lead a team, motivate others, and be an example of ethics in the workplace.\"", "\"I am thrilled to begin my career with Company ABC and will bring a variety of important transferable skills from my time as a student and an athlete. First, I know that you are seeking a team player who can lead without being asked. I am excellent at this, considering I was the captain of my soccer team, requiring me to play to everyone's strengths while remaining sportsmanlike in a competitive environment. As a student, I learned the importance of organization. I would plan my day and weeks according to which tasks and assignments were most urgent. These are just some of the qualities that I will bring to Company ABC should you choose to hire me.\""]}, {"topic": "Public+Transit", "question": "Every day is different at Company ABC; which requires patience and endurance. Are you a patient individual by nature?", "answers": ["Working with the public in significant volumes, as Company ABC does, you will have to be on your toes, ready to deal with situations that test your patience and endurance daily. Patience is a virtue because it does not always come easy! Be sure to highlight for the interviewer the ways that you exercise patience in your daily work life. It's vital that you express your ability to stay professional and calm no matter the situation.", "\"I am a patient person by nature when it comes to the public, people who need my help, or situations that require flexibility and fluidity. In my current position, my job duties are highly customer service based. I hear a lot of the same questions every day and work with the same customer grievances multiple times per week. I still treat every customer as they are their own person; never projecting feelings from one customer interaction to another. Rest assured, should you hire me at Company ABC, I will exercise the utmost professionalism in every situation.\"", "\"My post-secondary experience has shown me that I can be patient with myself and others. There have been times, during my university career, where the learning curve was steep, and I needed to apply myself without becoming frustrated by my lack of knowledge. There were other times where I needed to be patient on group projects when I felt that my teammates were not working as fast or efficiently as they could be. For these reasons, yes, I do consider myself to be a patient individual.\""]}, {"topic": "Public+Transit", "question": "What does exceptional customer service mean to you?", "answers": ["Company ABC strives to be the best in everything that they do; providing safety and comfort to the millions of people who ride with them every year. Think about your philosophy toward customer service. \n\nOne example of a customer service philosophy is that of Ken Blanchard, who said, 'Just having satisfied customers isn't good enough anymore. If you really want a booming business, you have to create raving fans.' \n\nTake some time to think about what is important to you as a consumer, and also as a person working in a customer-facing position. Be sure to show enthusiasm in your response!", "\"To me, exceptional customer service means that you treat the customer like they are your boss. He can take your job away if unsatisfied with your performance! For this reason, I treat every customer that I come across as though they are the ones signing my paycheck. I am attentive, respectful, and helpful at every opportunity.\"", "\"Exceptional customer service means that my primary goal is to make the life of every customer as easy as possible. Whether my interaction with them is just a moment in time, or if I communicate with them daily. I remember reading the quote by Teddy Roosevelt that says, 'People do not care how much you know until they know how much you care.' I believe this thinking should be applied to customer service, as well.\""]}, {"topic": "Public+Transit", "question": "Company ABC employees are trusted to be around passengers with valuables. Sometimes those valuables are left behind. What would you do if you found a purse full of cash left on one of our trains?", "answers": ["This question is all about honesty and integrity. The interviewer needs to know that you would choose to do the right thing, even when nobody is looking. The best way to answer this question is to give examples of integrity from your past. Because, as we all know, the best indicator of future behavior is past behavior. Integrity comes from being honest and being consistent with your moral values.", "\"If I were to come across a purse full of cash left on one of our trains, I would follow Company ABC protocol to a tee. It's important to me that I am trusted but also that I am kind. I would want someone to keep my belongings intact as well, should I lose something important. While working as an Uber driver, I had a passenger who lost a diamond earring during her ride. She called me the moment she noticed. I pulled over and looked for the earring and, sure enough, it had fallen between the seats. I could have lied and then sold the diamond; however, that is not something that I would do. Instead, I drove to her home and delivered the earring to her.\"", "\"Without integrity, what do we have? One example of honesty was when I was offered last years' answer key for my algebra final. I refused to take the answers even though I could have used the boost in my mark. If I were to find valuables on a train, I would contact the person right away and make arrangements for them to get their belongings back. I look forward to training at Company ABC where I am sure to learn more surrounding protocols for these types of situations.\""]}, {"topic": "Transportation", "question": "How can we motivate you on the job?", "answers": ["Every employer should know how each staff member is best motivated. Talk to the interviewer about the variety of ways in which you are best motivated on the job.", "\"I am best motivated through words of praise and recognition for a job well done. I do like to know that my efforts are being noticed. In my current position, we have a leaderboard, and I do like that concept because it creates a healthy bit of personal competition for me as well.\"", "Here are some ways that an employer may try to motivate you. Which ones resonate most with you? \n\n- Incentive programs where points are earned\n- Showing complete trust in your work and performance\n- Setting smaller, more achievable goals\n- Helping you to find your greater career purpose\n- Being a positive example to you \n- Maintaining an open and transparent workplace\n- Personalized incentives vs. Team driven incentives \n- Getting to know you on a personal level\n- Positive feedback based rewards system\n- Offering a healthy work/life balance by encouraging time off\n- Letting you know your voice matters\n- Allowing you to take the lead on projects that excite you \n- Handing out big-picture plans, so you feel that you are contributing to the company's future\n- Public recognition"]}, {"topic": "Transportation", "question": "Considering the multiple competitors that we have, why do you want to work for Company ABC?", "answers": ["Before your interview with Company ABC it's a great idea to get to know who their competitors are, and what makes Company ABC stand out from the rest. \n\nResearch online through a Google news search, or on the company website. If Company ABC has a 'News' or 'About Us' section on their website you will likely find some information on recent awards, industry accolades, etc.", "\"While researching Company ABC and the local market I did see that there are a few competitors in our area. What stood out to me was the enthusiasm of your team when I first applied here, and also the fact that you recently won the coveted Transportation Leadership Award. In addition to all of this, I see that Company ABC puts an important focus on carbon footprint. All of this makes you stand out from your competitors.\"", "\"From my research, I see that your business is the longest standing company in the area. Also, you have the most positive customer reviews online. After reading through your website, I saw a common theme of dedication to exceptional service and customer satisfaction. These are just some of the factors that make you stand out as the best potential employer in this industry.\""]}, {"topic": "Transportation", "question": "What are your salary expectations?", "answers": ["The best way to discuss your salary expectations is to use your current earnings as an example. Be open, and honest. Transparency is the best choice when salary based questions arise.", "\"Currently, I earn a base salary of $45,000 per year plus a potential 20% annual bonus. Last year my earnings were $52,000, and I would like to stay in the same range or slightly higher.\"", "\"I am currently making $60,000 per year with two bonus opportunities.  I am looking for compensation that is aligned with the role and provides an opportunity for growth.\""]}, {"topic": "Transportation", "question": "Describe an ongoing problem at your current or former employer that you were able to overcome.", "answers": ["Every place of employment will have its challenges. Talk to the interviewer about a specific issue that you were able to overcome in your previous role. Be sure to remain positive. Avoid complaining or saying negative things about your last employer or co-workers.", "\"In my most recent position we had an ongoing concern with our most popular stock depleting before the new shipment would come in. Customers would become annoyed and upset, which then became an issue for me as the Customer Service Manager. I decided to document the cycle and then approach the Inventory Manager about my concern. We were able to work on a solution for ordering from that particular supplier. In the end, this solved the majority of supply issues.\"", "\"A recurring problem that I have in my current position is the fact that our client management software is not user-friendly. Any entry that I need to make is incredibly time-consuming which poses a real problem when a deadline is present, or when we have clients waiting for an answer. I have found that the best workaround for this is not to allow my paperwork to build up. The more proactive I am, the better I can keep ahead of schedule.\""]}, {"topic": "Transportation", "question": "At Company ABC all of our transportation vehicles are outfitted with Qualcomm on-board computers. Do you have experience with this type of equipment?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like further details on the types of software, programs, and technical equipment with which you have experience.  How you rate your level of expertise will determine how much Company ABC will need to train you if selected for the position. Discuss your level of exposure to Qualcomm onboard computers or similar programs.", "\"I have approximately five years' experience with Qualcomm onboard computers and other similar systems used for GPS monitoring and communication. I would rate my abilities in this system as Intermediate.\"", "\"Although I have not worked with the Qualcomm system before, I do have experience with other onboard software. I am technically savvy and more than willing to start learning the Qualcomm system on my own time, before starting in this position.\""]}, {"topic": "Transportation", "question": "How would you describe your work ethic?", "answers": ["When the interviewer asks about your work ethic, they are looking for specific examples or keywords to which they can relate. When you read the company job, posting or job description do they refer to particular company ethics? Talk about their values and how those align well with your work values.", "\"I am a very dedicated and loyal employee. I saw on your website that you describe your company as honest, transparent and you go the extra mile for your clients. My work ethic is the same. I am honest, flexible, and come ready to work hard for my employer every day.\"", "Here are some other words to describe your work ethic:\n\n- Professional \n- Dedicated \n- Determined \n- Accountable\n- Driven \n- Strategic"]}, {"topic": "Transportation", "question": "When do you best demonstrate yourself as a leader?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to know that you are confident about your leadership abilities and that you understand when your leadership abilities have been most useful.\n\nPerhaps you best demonstrate yourself as a leader when your manager is away. Maybe you often jump into a leadership mindset when a co-worker is struggling. Think about a recent time when an employee on your team was successful at something because of your leadership skills. Discuss the scenario and how your leadership skills made the difference.", "\"I best demonstrate myself as a leader when I know that a coworker could use my assistance. I seem to be a natural teacher and mentor which means that when someone is struggling, my first instinct is to train them. Just recently, I coached a new employee on a sales technique that helped her to achieve her quota for the first time. I look forward to working in this role with you because it will allow me to take on further leadership opportunities.\"", "\"In my current position, every time my current manager is away, I take on the role of leader for our team. This opportunity usually comes one day per week. When you call him for a reference, he will be able to tell you that I have naturally stepped into the responsibilities associated with being a leader.\""]}, {"topic": "Transportation", "question": "List the top 3 skills that you have acquired in your last role.", "answers": ["You have likely gained many valuable skills in your career. Share with the interviewer which skills you value the most. Be sure to include capabilities that will potentially benefit this potential new employer.", "\"In the past few years I was able to upgrade my education while still working full time. The biggest skill that I gained was my ability to multi-task as I worked the dual role of employee and student. I also have strong skills in a variety of Microsoft programs such as PowerPoint and Excel.\"", "Here are some transferable skills that you may have acquired along the way:\n\n- Leading a team \n- Intricate problem solving \n- Particular software experience \n- Organizational training \n- Time management \n- Self-motivation \n- Listening skills\n- Written communication \n- Verbal communication \n- Giving presentations \n- Training new hires \n- Hiring or on-boarding\n- Research"]}, {"topic": "Transportation", "question": "Although we have a great training program at Company ABC, we are seeking to hire someone with an intermediate level of experience in our industry. What types of transportation services are you most experienced with?", "answers": ["Although the answer to this question may be on your resume, the interviewer would like for you to expand on your experience and give them a bright idea of your expertise level in their industry. Be sure to highlight the knowledge you have that directly relates to the business focus of Company ABC.", "\"The bulk of my experience in the transportation industry comes from my time as a dispatcher in Expedited & Emergency, Temperature Controlled, and Border Crossing focused transportation. I have approximately 12 years' experience total. I would rate myself as an intermediate to an expert level employee in most areas of transportation and freight.\"", "\"My experience in transportation services is vast. I have worked in this industry for the past ten years, primarily in heavy haul transportation. I do look forward to learning even more, through your training program.\""]}, {"topic": "Transportation", "question": "We seek to promote those who show initiative at Company ABC. Where would you like to see your career grow in the next 5 years?", "answers": ["Onboarding new employees is an expensive and time-consuming endeavor for any employer. Assure the interviewer that you see long-term career potential with Company ABC. It is highly recommended that you research the company online to discover any opportunities for future growth. Do they have multiple locations? Is there a variety of departments? Where do you see yourself growing within Company ABC? Be enthusiastic when you discuss your long-term career plans!", "\"I am looking for a long-term career opportunity within the transportation industry. I feel that this role with Company ABC is a perfect step in my career now, and for the future. I see that you have operations management positions open. My dream would be to earn a leadership role with Company ABC down the road.\"", "\"In 5 years I would like to be seen as an authority in our industry. I would like to be well-connected and trusted when it comes to my work here.\""]}, {"topic": "Transportation", "question": "How would you describe your written communication skills?", "answers": ["Being a clear communicator, in written form, is a critical skill to master. Have you taken any courses in communication and writing? Are you confident in your written communication skills? Talk to the interviewer about your written communication abilities and support your answer with a brief example or story.", "\"I would describe my written communication skills as very strong and would rate myself as a 9/10. I have always had a penchant for writing and have taken university courses related to communication, writing, and journalism.\"", "\"My written communication skills are powerful. I often utilize written communications as a follow up to verbal communications. They provide a great resource for associates to go back to, and reference, plus they might answer any questions that come up along the way.\""]}, {"topic": "Transportation", "question": "At Company ABC we connect businesses who need to ship their goods to companies who require those goods. This means that relationships are everything to us. What is your customer service philosophy?", "answers": ["Because Company ABC puts so much effort into their reputation, the interviewer needs to be confident that your philosophy on customer service aligns well with theirs. Be sure to research the Company ABC website and take note of any keywords they use when it comes to their clients and services. Match your language with theirs.", "\"I noticed on your website that you value your clients by actively listening to their needs. You also survey them regularly while staying on top of industry trends so that you can provide them with innovative new services. To me, customer service goes beyond friendliness and efficiency. You need to understand your customer's business needs and have the ability to analyze their future needs so that you can respond appropriately to their business landscape changes.\"", "\"My customer service philosophy is simple. I deliver the exact level of service to my customers that I would expect to receive, myself. Treating people with kindness is a simple first step to creating a strong and lasting customer relationship.\""]}, {"topic": "Transportation", "question": "We run Company ABC as a 24/7 operation. Do you have any limitations on your hours and availability?", "answers": ["If you have any restrictions in your schedule, now is the time to discuss those. If you are not sure of the hour's requirement for this job it is okay to ask the interviewer for further details before you give your reply.", "\"I understand that with a 24/7 operation there are many shifts available. Could you tell me more about what those look like?\"", "\"Because I have young children at home my preference would be to work as close as possible to their school schedules. With that said, I am always open to working overtime and covering shifts whenever needed.\""]}, {"topic": "Transportation", "question": "Because of the nature of business at Company ABC we conduct background checks on employees. This includes criminal background, credit, drivers abstract, and education verification checks.  Are you willing to comply?", "answers": ["Most companies in the transportation industry need to be very cautious about who they hire. There is a chance that much of the information you are going to access could be confidential and you may be assisting with the transport of dangerous goods. Assure the interviewer that you are most willing to comply with any form of background check they require.", "\"I am happy to comply with any background check required. My criminal and driving record is clean, and I have a strong credit history. I do not participate in drug use, either. You can be assured that if you hire me for this role with Company ABC, I will maintain a clean record.\"", "\"I fully understand why a complete background check would be required in this field of work. I am happy to comply with any checks that you need to conduct.\""]}, {"topic": "Transportation", "question": "If you could start your career over again, what direction would you take?", "answers": ["A hiring manager will be able to tell a lot about your personality by learning about your other career interests. If you could do anything over, what would you do, and why?", "\"I certainly do not regret the direction I have taken my career; however, if I had to start over in a new direction completely I would likely pursue my Degree in Education and become a teacher. Both of my parents were teachers, and they seemed to have a very fulfilling career. I enjoy coaching and leading others so, any tasks in my current career that related to these skills, are very welcome.\"", "\"I am delighted with the direction my career has taken. If I could change anything I would perhaps have furthered my education to include a unique focus; however, I have no regrets!\""]}, {"topic": "Transportation", "question": "How many days were you absent from work last year?", "answers": ["A part of being a diligent employee is to ensure that you are always on time and present when expected. It's great to even be 10 minutes early rather than just showing up right on the dot. Talk to the interviewer about your attendance.", "\"I had zero unexcused absences last year. In total, I took 12 vacation days out of my 15 allotted days. I was sick just 2, and a note from my Doctor accompanied those. Once I was late due to a terrible snow storm, and I always try to be 10 minutes early for my shift.\"", "\"I cannot recall the exact number, but I think it was around three days total. All absences were excused and with notice.\""]}, {"topic": "Transportation", "question": "Company ABC provides transport services to a multitude of clients. What do you know about our clientele and the channels of business we service?", "answers": ["Before your interview, be sure to research Company ABC and the types of clients and businesses they serve. In addition to their website, a quick Google search could tell you a lot about their clients and business channels. Give your best answer and be sure to ask the interviewer for further details. The more you know, the better off you will be in the next step of interviews with Company ABC!", "\"From the research I have conducted, my understanding is that you service businesses primarily within Retail, Automotive, Industrial, Food & Beverage, and Chemical. Is this correct? I would love to learn more.\"", "\"I have researched your organization quite a bit and am impressed with the range of business and clientele to which you provide transportation services. From my understanding, you primarily service manufacturing clients who consider themselves to be small to medium-sized operations. I see that you have many longstanding relationships  with your clients and that much of your business comes from a core group of returning clients.\""]}, {"topic": "Transportation", "question": "Productivity and communication are our top concerns at Company ABC. In your opinion, what suffers the most when synergy between dispatcher and driver is not present?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know that you have a natural tendency to think about the good of the business and that you understand how important clear communication is within the transportation industry. Talk a little bit about the aspects of business you feel suffer the most when communication is not healthy between dispatcher and driver.", "\"When communication is not strong between a driver and dispatch, it can become a costly problem. When there is a strong synergy between the two, a company can significantly reduce fuel consumption and greatly improve customer service.\"", "\"What suffers most when synergy between dispatcher and driver is not present, is team morale. When communication is strong, employees want to stay in their jobs, they work harder, and are more motivated to make an effort for their company.\""]}, {"topic": "Transportation", "question": "The transportation industry is ever-changing. At Company ABC we seek to hire individuals with a keen interest in this industry. How do you stay up to date on transportation related current events?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to confirm that you have a genuine interest in the transportation industry. Perhaps you read transport related magazines, follow particular mechanical journals or subscribe to a blog related to this industry. Briefly share with the interviewer how you stay up to date on current events related to Company ABC.", "\"I am always interested in learning more about this industry and the changes that are taking place. Most frequently, I read Canadian Trucking Magazine. There are also a couple of blogs that I follow including NADA Commercial Truck Blog and TruckingTruth.\"", "\"It is a challenge to stay up to date on the transportation industry, with policy changing on a regular basis. The most reliable source that I utilize is 'Transport Topics.' With that said, I love to learn about new resources. Would you mind sharing with me your favorite source of transportation-related news?\""]}, {"topic": "Transportation", "question": "When you suffer a setback, how does that emotionally affect you and your work?", "answers": ["Everyone handles the stress and disappointment of setbacks differently. Discuss with the interviewer how you typically cope with delays in the workplace.", "\"Experiencing a setback is always disappointing, and can be a bit disheartening, but I understand that it happens from time to time. If I experience a major setback, I will take a few moments to debrief with my manager and discuss what I could have done differently. Then, I move on!\"", "\"Setbacks happen for a reason, and they do not affect me emotionally in the least. I am a very pragmatic thinker and stay focused despite the challenges that come my way.\""]}, {"topic": "Transportation", "question": "When have you had to make a split second decision? How do you react under unexpected pressure?", "answers": ["Being able to make quick decisions and think fast on your feet sets top-notch professionals out from the crowd.  We all make a lot of choices every day, so start off by telling the interviewer that you make a lot of quick decisions each day.  Next, be prepared for a more significant example that will be sure to impress.", "\"My current position requires me to make tough decisions on a regular basis. I work well under pressure like that. With split-second decisions, I will always go with my initial instinct. Last week, I had two high-profile clients show up for a meeting at the same time. One client was late, and the other was early. I did not want anyone to feel bad for being late or too early, so I had each party placed in a different conference room. My colleague started the meeting with our early meeting while I met with the client who was late. It worked out well because I am no stranger to multi-tasking and I have great support staff.\"", "\"In my current fast-paced role, this happens often! We handle a lot of customer situations and put them first and foremost.  Often, we have guidelines we follow, and there are also times when situations call for creative solutions to meet customer needs.  I make split-second decisions when resolving these matters in the best interest of the customer and the company.\""]}, {"topic": "Transportation", "question": "How would you describe your personality?", "answers": ["Personality and character are two very different things. The interviewer is looking for more information on your traits vs. your integrity. These traits could include buzzwords such as introverted, energetic, and confident.", "\"I would describe my personality as approachable, light-hearted, and positive. I believe that, if asked, my colleagues and supervisor would say the same about me.\"", "Here are some words you can use to describe your personality: \n\n- Adaptable \n- Compassionate \n- Exuberant\n- Inventive\n- Persistent\n- Reliable \n- Sincere \n- Witty"]}, {"topic": "Transportation", "question": "When have you had to think outside of the box to solve a problem?", "answers": ["Talk to the interviewer about a time that you have solved a problem solved creatively. Were you happy with the outcome?", "\"In my current position we saw a decrease in clients due to a local economic downturn. I recommended to our head office that we begin to generate business outside of our region for the first time in many years. They agreed, and the idea turned things around for us that fiscal year.\"", "\"I once had to deal with a space issue in our warehouse.  We arranged and re-arranged several times and could not make it work.  I thought outside the box and rented some outside pod storage until we were back to normal inventory levels.\""]}, {"topic": "Transportation", "question": "When you have a problem at work are you one to carefully consider what is at stake or do you jump in and hope for the best?", "answers": ["It is essential to be able to quickly, yet effectively, assess an issue in the workplace. Talk to the interviewer about how you handle a problem at work.", "\"I have been with my current company for many years, so the majority of problem-solving comes second nature to me at this point. However, when I first started this job, I would have to spend more time in careful consideration before jumping in. I would say that when I have a problem, I have a healthy balance of the two.\"", "\"That depends on the situation and seriousness of the problem.  I will not jump in with rash decisions on a problem that has a major impact on our business, but I will change coffee vendors on a whim to save money or increase satisfaction.\""]}, {"topic": "Transportation", "question": "Do you think honesty is always the best policy?", "answers": ["Is honesty always the best policy? Talk to the interviewer about your thoughts on honesty in the workplace.", "\"Sometimes full disclosure can damage someone's self-esteem, and reality isn't always best expressed in full and can be self-indulgent based on the person's intention. In those instances, honesty isn't always the best policy.\"", "\"Honesty is always the best policy.  Often, it is just a matter of how you communicate and deliver your message so managing this with each situation is critical to building honest and trustworthy relationships.\""]}, {"topic": "Transportation", "question": "What personal traits do you look for in people you are hiring?", "answers": ["Everyone has a \"type,\" even in the workplace. Talk to the interviewer about the characteristics and personality types that you tend to hire and why you lean that way.", "\"I look at experience and qualifications but most of all, I seek relational competence.  Someone who has the personality and fit to thrive in our fast-paced environment. When you have all of those things, you can truly fire on all cylinders.\""]}, {"topic": "Transportation", "question": "How do you balance life and work?", "answers": ["It is essential to keep a healthy work/life balance to prevent burnout. Talk to the interviewer about how you can maintain that appropriate balance for yourself.", "\"I find that with the right company, it's pretty simple to balance life and work. When I enjoy what I do it doesn't feel like a chore. I am always sure that when at home, my family gets my attention first. I take time on the weekends to do things for myself and ensure that I regenerate before the work week begins.\"", "\"I ensure a strong balance between life and work by spending my free time doing the things that I love. I will go mountain biking, or take my kids to the swimming pool. By making the most of my personal time, I regenerate and perform better at work.\""]}, {"topic": "Transportation", "question": "What sources do you look to when solving complicated problems?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to know that you can think outside the box, or even ask for help when you are stuck on a complicated problem.\n\nMaybe you look to a mentor or boss for advice. Perhaps you have handbooks, manuals and systems you turn to for help. Offer some relevant examples based on your industry. If you work in the medical field, you may turn to textbooks, online research, colleagues or even patient's history to find the right solution. If you work in customer service, you may ask the customer what they need to find the best way to solve the problem. \n\nShow the interviewer that you are knowledgeable and equipped to handle these types of scenarios.", "\"When faced with a complicated problem, I will look to the resources that my current company has provided me. The answer is almost always in there. If it's more of a moral dilemma vs. a knowledge-based dilemma, I will ask my supervisor for his thoughts and opinion since I value him as a mentor and expert in our industry.\"", "\"To solve a complex issue, I will reach out to a manager or mentor from a previous role to ask them how they've handled such issues in the past. I am always ready to dive back into our handbook, but these types of scenarios are often not covered there, which is why I value a human, experiential approach. I know that there are so many folks in the industry who have so much to teach me and have probably already \"been-there-done-that,\" so I love to utilize them as a resource.\""]}, {"topic": "Transportation", "question": "What could your current employer do for you that would have prevented you from looking for a new job?", "answers": ["There are just a few reasons why an employee would want to leave their current position. Talk to the interviewer about your reasons for moving on and what could have prevented you from starting your employment search. Be sure to avoid speaking negatively about your current employer.", "\"What prompted my search was a reduction in hours and a pending lay off in the fall due to lack of business. I am satisfied with the majority of aspects when it comes to my current position, but it just isn't providing for me financially.\"", "\"All employees want is to feel valued, appreciated, and to make a good living. My current employer is relocating to another state, and I am not interested in relocating. Other than that - they fulfilled my needs as an employee, in most ways.\""]}, {"topic": "Transportation", "question": "How long have you been looking for a job?", "answers": ["Talk to the interviewer about your job search. Have you been on the lookout for a long time? How successful has your search been? You can also ask the interviewer how quickly they are hoping to hire.", "\"I have been on the search for perhaps a month or so. I am now just beginning to become more aggressive in my job search. How quickly are you looking to make a decision?\"", "\"I am a passive job seeker who is keeping abreast of opportunities that are right for me. I think it's best to look for a new position while currently working. It prevents rash decisions made out of desperation.\""]}, {"topic": "Transportation", "question": "Do you believe it is possible to be a good team member yet disagree with the leader?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to know that you can be diplomatic in the workplace, even when you may not agree with your leader. \n\nShow the interviewer that it is possible for you to be a good team member, yet disagree with the leader from time to time. Explain that you believe everyone is entitled to their own professional opinion, yet capable of maintaining respect for each other at the same time. \n\nShow that even if you disagree with the final decision they make, you support the direction the team is heading.", "\"I think that it is possible to be a great team member, even when disagreeing with the leader. It's all in how you maintain respect for each other despite the difference in opinion.\"", "\"Yes, I think it is possible! What makes a great team member is not that they agree with everything but the level of respect and positive thought that goes into the person's communication style. It's okay to disagree; you just have to communicate your thoughts professionally.\""]}, {"topic": "Transportation", "question": "You have a couple of gaps in your resume. Can you explain these?", "answers": ["When responding to this question, make sure you answer honestly about your gaps of employment, whether your gaps are due to staying home with the kids, an illness, taking care of an ailing parent, or taking some time off to think about a career change.", "\"The first gap in my resume was from 2007 - 2008 when I took a year off after completing University, to travel. Even though I was not working, I learned so much about business and interpersonal communication during that year of travel. After being laid off in 2012, I was without work for six months. Those are the only two gaps in my resume.\"", "\"Absolutely!  There were two times where I had a gap in my career.  One gap was taking time off for personal reasons in between a great career pivot.  The other, I took some time off to attend schooling for a certificate to be better at my work.\""]}]